CINDY SOH

• DETAILS •

Singapore +6591394711 cindysoh90@gmail.com

> Nationality Singaporean

· LINKS ·

LinkedIn

<u>Github</u>

SKILLS

Python

SQL

Microsoft Excel

Microsoft PowerPoint

Microsoft Outlook

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator

LANGUAGES

English

Chinese

PROFILE

Experienced Planner with a demonstrated history of working in the retail industry. Skilled in Microsoft Excel, Customer Service, Retail, Sales, and Marketing Strategy. Strong business development professional with a Bachelor of Arts - BA focused in Fashion design and textile from LASALLE College of the Arts. Strong interest in Data Analytics. Using Machine Learning software for forecasting and inventory planning at work sparked my interest in Data Science, Machine Learning, Algorithms, and automation. Inspired to create a better and more efficient working environment for everyone in the company.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Assortment Planner at Nike, Singapore

September 2022 — Present

Work closely with Finance, Operation, and Merchant | Focus on assortment demand planning for Singapore distributors | Forecast assortment quarterly | Prepare Singapore monthly sales report | Monitor and advise partners on inventory planning |

Stretch role: Location Planner

Monthly forecast Singapore, Malaysia, and Thailand store KPI targets | Prepare seasonal roll-up | Maintain daily sales report | Review monthly aging inventory

Assistant Brand Planner at Williams-Sonoma, Inc., Singapore

December 2021 — Present

Work closely with Brand Manager, Order Management team, Merchant | Focus on demand planning for UK market for West Elm | Forecast monthly OTB, Pre-meet, Reorder report | Plan weekly promotion and markdown | Prepare seasonal Investment Review report | Maintain healthy levels and distribution of stocks | Review SKU performance monthly | Weekly business review on sales, promotion and inventory | In charge of weekly allocation for UK market

Merchandising Executive at Vintage Sport Pte Ltd, Singapore

January 2021 — December 2021

Work closely with Brand Manager, Retail, Marketing, and E-commerce | Manages Brands for Singapore and Malaysia markets such as CAT, Sperry, Nautica & Everlast | Plan product ranges, OTB, and prices | Meeting with suppliers and distributors | Weekly & monthly sales and inventory report | Planning quantities and delivery timescales | Maintain healthy levels of inventory | Handling supply/production problems | Setting stock promotions/price reductions | Quarterly reports to Management | Analyze sales performance/sell-through of different collections | Manage E-commerce customer service

E-commerce Merchandiser at SK Jewellery, Singapore

October 2018 — January 2021

Work closely with Marketing, In-Stock & Retail Operations | Manages 3 marketplaces and official website for both SK Jewellery and Love & Co. | Maintain pricing strategy | Product development and planning | Campaign planning for various marketplace | Order fulfillment | Monitor inventory | Prepare MTD and YTD Report (Sales and Inventory) as well as sales analysis | Prepare Purchase Order | Weekly stock distribution based on sales analysis | Liaise with supplier on orders and delivery

Pattern Drafter at Time Taken To Make a Dress, Singapore

October 2014 — October 2018

Work closely with Designers and Seamstress | Assist designer with procurement of fabrics | Completion of customised gowns | Attend to client's fittings | Manage client's expectation and alterations

Retail Assistant at Christian Dior, Singapore

May 2010 — May 2011

Small Leather Goods Specialist | Work closely with Buyer and Visual Merchandiser | Attend to client's need for all Category in store | Coordinated efficient restocking of the sales floor with current season merchandise

EDUCATION

Data Science Immersive, General Assembly, Singapore

August 2022 — March 2023

BA Fashion Design & Textile, Lasalle College of the Arts, Singapore

May 2011 — May 2014

Diploma in Retail Management, Temasek Polytechnic, Singapore

April 2007 — April 2010

INTERNSHIPS

Intern at Marchesa, New York City

November 2012 — January 2013

COURSES

Diamond Foundation Course, De Beers Group Institute of Diamonds

July 2020 — July 2020

Data Science Bootcamp, Vertical Institute

April 2022 — April 2022